

Ruben Caliandro

Full-stack Web Developer, Game Programmer

CONTACT

Website http://chosko.com

Email ruben.caliandro@gmail.com

Phone (+39) 333 736 8333

Location Torino, IT

Profiles

Github https://github.com/chosko

Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/rubencaliandro/en

Personal http://chosko.com

I have a strong interest in Computer Graphics and Videogames since I was 15. I use to develop videogames in my spare time, and I try to attend game jams around the world, as I did in Torino, Roma and San Francisco

ABOUT

I am also a Web Developer since 2010. I worked in companies located in Italy (Torino) and USA (Sunnyvale, CA).

Even though I'm always working, my passion for Computer Graphics brought me to keep studying at the University after getting the Bachelor's Degree with honors. Currently I'm taking a Master of Science in Virtual Reality and Multimedia. I have two exams left and I'm trying hard to get the best result (expected is 110/110).

Work Experience

Full-stack Web Developer at Tandù srl: (http://tandu.it)

Project Management and Full-Stack Development.

- Main technologies: Node.js/Express, Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, AWS ElasticBeanstalk, Docker, CircleCl

♥ TURIN, ITALY

MAY, 2015 − PRESENT

O 1 YEAR 1 MONTH

SUNNYVALE, CA, USA

∰ Jul, 2014 — Ост, 2014

O 3 MONTHS

Front-end Web Developer at Eversnap: (http://www.geteversnap.com/home.html)

Front-end Development

- Web application development (front-end) using AngularJS
- Project architecture refactoring
- Automatic tools and CI with git, GruntJS and Fabric
- Development process used: Scrum

♥ TURIN, ITALY

∰ Jan, 2013 — Jan, 2014

O 1 YEAR

Web Application Developer at MyTable:

Full-Stack Development

- Web Application Design and Development (both Client and Server-Side).
- Design and Development of some Ruby Gems (and Rails Engines).
- Skills: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, MySQL, UML

♥ TURIN, ITALY

> ② 2 YEARS 10 MONTHS

Web Application Developer at Condominioitalia Editrice:

Web Development

- Web Application Design, Developement and Graphics.
- Private Network and PCs Maintenance.
- Recording and Editing of the online news 'TG del Condominio'.
- Skills: PHP, MySQL, (X)HTML, Javascript.

VOLUNTEER

② 3 YEARS 9 MONTHS

Film Projectionist, Cinema Teatro Cuore:

35mm Film Projections, in week-end film shows.

- Film assembling and deassembling.
- Security checks.
- Website maintenance.
- Film projections with manual changeovers, using two Cinemeccanica Victoria 8.

EDUCATION

∰ Jan, 2013 — Present

EXPECTED SCORE: 110/110

Università degli studi di Torino - Computer Science Department

Master of Science: Computer Graphics, Virtual Reality and Multimedia

- MFN0978 Virtual Reality Systems 30/30 cum laude
- MFN0947 Multimedia Database 28/30
- MFN0972 Digital Image Processing and Artificial Vision 30/30
- MFN0970 Physics for Virtual Reality 30/30
- MFN0942 Artificial Intelligence 30/30
- MFN0973 3D Graphics Modeling 30/30 cum laude
- MFN0962 Numerical Methods 20/30
- MFN0960 Concurrent Models and Distributed Algorithms 30/30
- MFN0963 English II Approved
- MFN0961 Information Theory 27/30
- MFN0949 Cognitive Systems 30/30
- MFN0951 Bioinformatics To do
- MFN0977 Neural Networks To do

Score: 110/110 CUM LAUDE

Università degli studi di Torino - Computer Science Department

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science (Networks)

Thesis: Spam Analysis tools

High School P. Gobetti

High School: Science

Thesis: Mathematics applied to the 3D Computer-Graphics Programming

PROJECTS

₩ FEB, 2015

Lazy (http://www.chosko.com/en/video_games/lazy.html) — Videogame

Lazy is the video game who doesn't want to be played. Starting from the main menu, everything seems like the game is not willing to play with you, and he will try everything to make you exit.

- An award won
- Keywords: 3D Game, First Person, Unity3D, Cross-Platform

Battle Bugs (http://www.chosko.com/en/video_games/battlebugs.html#content-top) — Videogame

Battle Bugs has been developed by the team in 48h for the Alpha Game Jam, in San Francisco. The goal of this strategy game is to defend your home hive and destroy the enemy hive, or defeat all the enemy bugs

- An award won
- Keywords: 2D Game, Strategy, Unity3D, Cross-Platform

₩ Nov, 2013

ScrollCraft (http://www.windowsphone.com/it-it/store/app/scrollcraft/8f7c61d3-9f2b-4092-b02d-212519f872d8)

— Videogame

Developed in 48hours, during the international Indie Speed Run 2013. It is an endless runner featuring the theme and the element assigned to the team: Speed and Scroll.

- Two awards won (4th place Best 2D Graphics, 4th place Best Animation)
- Keywords: 2D Game, MonoGame, C#, Cross-Platform
- Team members: Roberto Pesando, Stefano Nada, Stefano Ordine and I

₩ JUL, 2013

AMCG (https://github.com/psicomante/aamcg) — Videogame

Another Multiplayer Cuboids Game: a game developed in less than a month with Unity, cubes and C#. It features a semi-random map generation with support for mobile accelerometer that allows to control the player.

- Network and GUI System Development
- Shading and Graphics Effect Development
- Client instances of the game used only as controllers (Mobile accelerometer + Controls GUI)
- Server instance used as the only shared display (running on PC/Mac)
- Keywords: Unity3D, C#, GLSL, Network Multiplayer
- Team members: Roberto Pesando and I

MAPR, 2013

Minesweeper3D (https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/8771146/Minesweeper3D.zip) — Videogame

This video game is the 3D version of the classic Minesweeper. I developed it during a weekend, because I could not find on the internet any game like this. The puzzle is really hard to solve, the mean resolution time for a 10x10x15 grid is about an hour.

- Keywords: 3D Game, Puzzle Game, XNA, C#
- Team members: Me

∰ Jan, 2010 — Jan, 2013

Continuum (https://github.com/xteamdimension/continuum-arena) — Videogame

Continuum is a 2D space shooter with time travel, developed for Windows Phone 7 with XNA (MonoGame). The goal is to control a space ship, destroying enemies and collecting weapons and power-ups. The peculiarity is that you can collect "tachyon streams" that allow you to rewind and warp the time if you are damaged.

- Keywords: 2D Game, Space Shooter, XNA, Windows Phone, Time Travel.
- Team members: Stefano Nada, Stefano Ordine and I

∰ Apr, 2009 — Jul, 2009 Mathematics applied to 3D Computer-Graphics programming (https://github.com/Chosko/high-school-thesis) — 3D Simulation, High School Thesis

A 3D Simulation of the Solar System built with C# directly on top of the DirectX 9 (no Frameworks, no Engines), presented as a thesis demonstration at the end of the High School

- Keywords: 3D Simulation, DirectX, C#, HLSL shaders, High School Thesis
- Team members: Me

Awards

SECOND PLACE

Aug 15, 2014

Alpha Game Jam 2014, San Francisco

The award has been won with the game Battle Bugs, a strategy 2D game made with Unity

THIRD PLACE

☐ FEB 23, 2015

Global Game Jam 2015, Turin Competition

The award has been won with the game Lazy, the game who doesn't want to be played. Made with Unity4.6

FOURTH PLACE (BEST 2D GRAPHICS), FOURTH PLACE (BEST ANIMATION)

M Nov 03, 2013

Indie Speed Run 2013, Rome Competition

The award has been won with the game Scrollcraft, an endless runner developed with C# and Monogame

Languages

Italian Native speaker

English Professional working proficiency

Interests

Guitar: Electric Guitar, Classical Guitar

Film Projectionism: 35mm films, Cinemeccanica Victoria 8, Dolby SR Rack Audio

Rubik's Cube: up to 4x4x4, learning Fridrich method **Video editing:** Adobe AfterEffects, Adobe Premiere